Betty Blanc Glassbury Papers
Betty Blanc Glassbury Papers
1944-1966
Glassbury, Betty Blanc.
0.5 linear ft.
American poet. Collection includes manuscript poems and a small amount of printed material.
149004
Biographical History
Betty Blanc Glassbury (dates unknown) was an American poet. Her works have been published in the United States, Canada, England and Australia. She served as president of the Composers, Authors and Artists of America and the National League of Creative Artists, and was an active member of various arts-related organizations including the Chopin Society and the Ziegfeld Club.
Glassbury was also a well-known opera singer and a traveler, linguist and collector of Tibetan art. Following her operatic career she turned to art, painting and working in ceramics.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Betty Blanc Glassbury Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, manuscripts and published material.
Correspondence contains two incoming letters. Subject files include awards and clippings. Manuscripts consists of poetry written by Glassbury. Published material includes newspaper clippings about Glassbury and several issues of Composers, Authors and Artists of America.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical.
Subject and Genre Headings
Women Authors; Literature -- American Poetry; Glassbury, Betty Blanc.; Women poets, American.; Poems.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, 1966 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Certificates, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Clippings about, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Clippings about others, 1966 (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Poems (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Magazine, Composers, Authors and Artists of America, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clipping about, 1965 (Box 1)